Guide to the Texas Society of Professional Engineers Houston Auxiliary Records
University of Houston Libraries
Texas Society of Professional Engineers Houston Auxiliary Records
1959-2013
1970-1999
02/2014-010
Texas Society of Professional Engineers. Houston Chapter. Auxiliary
25.00 linear feet
Special Collections, University of Houston Libraries
This collection contains items created between 1959 and 2013 related to the Texas Society of Professional Engineers (TSPE) and their Auxiliary, with a concentration on the Houston branch. The materials are broken up into series and organized chronologically within those series, with particular attention given to the original organization of the materials. There are meeting minutes, president’s records, relevant publications, and other miscellanea.
Historical Note:
The Texas Society of Professional Engineers (TSPE) Houston Auxiliary was established as a chapter of the National Society of Professional Engineers (NSPE) Auxiliary in 1960. The Auxiliary raises scholarship funds, campaigns, and provides support to the National Society of Professional Engineers. TSPE coordinates various continuing education programs, scholarship fundraising, MathCounts, the Houston Science Fair, and is active within the Engineering Council of Houston.
Access Terms
This Collection is indexed under the following controlled access subject terms.
Corporate Name:
Texas Society of Professional Engineers; Texas Society of Professional Engineers. Houston Chapter. Auxiliary
Genre/Form of Material:
Financial records; Minutes (administrative records); Programs (documents); Publications (document genre); Scrapbooks
Topical Term:
Engineers; Lobbying; Mentoring
Conditions Governing Access:
Open for research
Acquisition Information
Information of acquisition method not available.
Scope and Contents
This collection contains items created between 1959 and 2013 related to the Texas Society of Professional Engineers (TSPE) and their Auxiliary, with a concentration on the Houston branch. The materials are broken up into series and organized chronologically within those series, with particular attention given to the original organization of the materials. There are meeting minutes, president’s records, relevant publications, and other miscellanea.
Detailed List of Contents
- Point / Counterpoint, id165783
  - Programs, id165784
    - 1983-1984, id165787 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - 1984-1985, id165817 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - 1986-1987, id165818 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - 1987-1988, id165819 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - 1988-1989, id165820 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - 1989-1990, id165821 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - 1990-1991, id165822 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - 1991-1993, id165823 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - 1993-1995, id165824 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - 1995-1996, id165825 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - 1996-1997, id165826 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - 1997-1998, id165827 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - 1998-1999, id165828 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - 1999-2000, id165829 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - 2000-2001, id165830 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - 2001-2002, id165831 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - 2002-2003, id165833 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - 2003-2004, id165834 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - 2004-2005, id165835 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - 2005-2006, id165836 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - 2006-2007, id165837 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - 2007-2008, id165838 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Planning, id165839
    - 1982-1991, id165841 (Box 17, Folder 3-5)
    - 1992-1999, id167645 (Box 17, Folder 6-7)
    - 1999-2005, id165852 (Box 7, Folder 10-12)
- Auxiliary Yearbooks, id165855
  - Texas Society of Professional Engineers (TSPE), 1959-1980; id167742 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - TSPE, 1980-2000; id167743 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - TSPE, 2001-2013; id167744 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - National Society of Professional Engineers (NSPE), 1973; id167745 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Press and Newsletters, id165856
  - Texas Professional Engineer Magazine, July 1988-December 1989; id167651 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Texas Professional Engineer Magazine, May 1990-December 1991; id167652 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Texas Professional Engineer Magazine, March 1992-June 1995; id167653 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - The Professional Engineer San Jacinto Newsletter, May 1989-October 1991; id167675 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - The Professional Engineer San Jacinto Newsletter, February 1992-August 1996; id167676 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - TSPE Chapter Communicator, June 1989-May 1992; id167677 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - TSPE Auxiliary Newsletters, November 1989-January 1998; id167678 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - “Harper honored as Engineer of Year,” Houston Chronicle, February 1991; id167739 (Ovsbox 15, Folder 3)
  - “James Green: ’89 Engineer of the Year,” Houston Post, February 1989; id167740 (Ovsbox 15, Folder 4)
- Financials, id165857
  - 1991-1992, id167761 (Box 17, Folder 14)
  - 1995-1996, id167764 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - 1996-1997, id167765 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - 1997-1998, id167766 (Box 3, Folder 7-8)
  - 1998-1999, id167768 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - 1999-2000, id167769 (Box 3, Folder 10-11)
  - 2000-2001, id167771 (Box 3, Folder 12-13)
  - 2008-2009, id167773 (Box 3, Folder 14-15)
  - 2002-2012, id167788 (Box 4, Folder 1-2)
- Organizational Records, id165858
  - Treasurers' Records, id167790
    - 1990-1991, id167816 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - 2001-2003, id167817 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - 2004-2005, id167818 (Box 4, Folder 5-6)
    - 2006-2007, id167820 (Box 4, Folder 7-8)
    - 2009-2010, id167822 (Box 4, Folder 9-10)
    - 2010-2011, id167824 (Box 4, Folder 11-12)
    - 2012-2013, id167826 (Box 4, Folder 13-14)
    - 1999-2001, id167836 (Box 17, Folder 1-2)
  - Presidents' Records, id167791
    - Patricia Lawler's Records, 1986-1987; id167844 (Box 5, Folder 1-2)
    - Maurine Cosby's Records, 1987-1988; id167846 (Box 5, Folder 3-4)
    - TSPE Chapter Handbook, 1987; id167848 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - TSPE Chapter Handbook, 1988; id167849 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Barbara Clinton's Records, 1985-1986; id167850 (Box 7, Folder 1-3)
    - Lois Moke's Records, 2007-2008; id167853 (Box 7, Folder 4-5)
    - TSPE Chapter Handbook, 1989; id167855 (Box 17, Folder 8-9)
    - TSPE Chapter Handbook, 1990; id167857 (Box 17, Folder 10-11)
    - TSPE Chapter Handbook, 1991; id167859 (Box 17, Folder 12-13)
  - Meeting Minutes, id167792
    - 1967-1968, id167896 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - 1970-1975, id167897 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - 1975-1976, id167898 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - 1977-1979, id167899 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - 1980, id167900 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - 1982, id167901 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - 1990-1991, id167902 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - 1996, id167903 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - 1999-2006, id167904 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Miscellaneous Organizational Papers, id167793
    - Member registration forms, 1995-1996; id167919 (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - TSPE Membership Directories, 1990-1996; id167920 (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - Programs and Brochures, 1990-1997; id167921 (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - Miscellaneous Auxiliary paperwork, undated; id167924 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence, 1989-2001; id167925 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Event guest lists, 1966-1993; id167926 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Blank letterheads, undated; id167927 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Photographs, undated; id167928 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence, 1990; id167932 (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - NSPE Handbook, 1989; id167933 (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - NSPE Officer and Committee Directory, 1996-1997; id167934 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Scrapbooks, Guestbooks, and Ephemera, id167794
    - Scrapbook, 1977-1978; id167967 (Ovsbox 8, Item 1)
    - Scrapbook, 1983-1984; id167968 (Ovsbox 8, Item 2)
    - Scrapbook, 1973-1977; id167972 (Ovsbox 9, Item 1)
    - Scrapbook, 1981-1982; id167973 (Ovsbox 9, Item 2)
    - Scrapbook, 2006-2007; id167976 (Ovsbox 10, Item 1)
    - “Greatest member involvement in projects”, 1995; id167977 (Ovsbox 10, Item 2)
    - "Certificate of Special Recognition”, 1996; id167978 (Ovsbox 10, Item 3)
    - Miscellaneous scrapbook pages, loose, undated; id167979 (Ovsbox 10, Item 4)
    - Scrapbook, 1992-1993; id167982 (Ovsbox 11, Item 1)
    - Guestbook, September 1975; id167983 (Ovsbox 11, Item 2)
    - Guestbook, 2007; id167984 (Ovsbox 11, Item 3)
    - Guestbook, 1996; id167985 (Ovsbox 11, Item 4)
    - Guestbook, 1981-1982; id167986 (Ovsbox 11, Item 5)
    - Scrapbook, 1984-1986; id167991 (Ovsbox 12, Item 1)
    - Yellow toy airplane, undated; id167992 (Ovsbox 12, Item 2)
    - Gold-toned necklace with clear beads, undated; id167993 (Ovsbox 12, Item 3)
    - Scrapbook, 1968-1973; id167994 (Ovsbox 12, Item 4)
    - Scrapbook, August 1988-April 1990; id168003 (Ovsbox 13, Item 1)
    - Scrapbook, September 2009-March 2011; id168004 (Ovsbox 13, Item 2)
    - Scrapbook, September 1986-May 1988; id168007 (Ovsbox 14, Item 1)
    - Scrapbook, 1959-1968; id168008 (Ovsbox 14, Item 2)
    - Scrapbook, September 1994-May 1997; id168010 (Ovsbox 15, Item 1)
    - Scrapbook, 1990-1992; id168011 (Ovsbox 15, Item 2)
    - Scrapbook, 2003-2004; id168013 (Ovsbox 16, Item 1)
    - Scrapbook pages, 2004-2005; id168014 (Ovsbox 16, Item 2)
    - Scrapbook of Presidents, 2003-2004; id168015 (Ovsbox 16, Item 3)
  - National Society of Professional Engineers Conventions, id167795
    - NSPE scholarships, undated; id168048 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Louisville, 1995; id168050 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Detroit, 2001; id168051 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Hawaii, 1988; id168052 (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Anchorage, 2001; id168053 (Box 7, Folder 9)